Guide to the Pacific University Press Releases and Clippings Collection 1914-2003
Pacific University Archives
Pacific University Press Releases and Clippings Collection
1914-2003
RG.4.110
Pacific University, Archives http://www.pacificu.edu/library/services/archives/ 2043 College Way Forest Grove, OR, 97116 503-352-1405 archives@pacificu.edu
26.5 cubic feet 9 boxes, 1 oversize box, 4 folio boxes and 19 folio volumes
This collection contains newspaper clippings about Pacific University, mostly pasted into scrapbooks, from the 1870s-2000s. It also includes loose clippings and press release files.
Pacific University
Historical Note
Various departments and individuals at Pacific University have collected newspaper clippings about the school since the 19th century. By the 1920s, clippings were being systematically collected and compiled into scrapbooks. Most of the scrapbooks were probably compiled by the Publicity Department or related departments of the University. By the 1940s, the University was subscribing to a clippings service, which supplied clippings about the University, accompanied by tickets stamped with the date and title of the newspaper where the articles appeared. These clippings were normally compiled into scrapbooks, but were sometimes left loose. This process of acquiring clippings from a commercial service and then creating scrapbooks appears to have continued from the 1940s through the early 1990s.
In the late 1990s, the Publicity Office began saving its press releases, and filing them with clippings of any articles that were published based upon them. They appear to have discontinued making scrapbooks at that time.
In addition to the scrapbooks and press release files, various individuals associated with Pacific University independently collected loose clippings. Several people who may have been involved in saving clippings include Irene Story and Rick Read, who were involved with the Old College Hall Museum. Female students in the Herrick Hall dormitory may also have collected some of the earliest clippings records, though the records are unclear.
Collection is open for research.
Additional accruals are expected.
This collection contains press clippings about Pacific University, mostly pasted into scrapbooks. These scrapbooks begin in the 1920s. The clippings from the 1940s through the early 1990s are mostly accompanied by stamped tickets that record the date and newspaper from which them came. The clippings from 1998-2003 are accompanied by the press releases that generated the news stories. Two boxes of loose clippings from various sources cover the late 19th century through the 20th century.
Pacific University
Advertising and Marketing
Clippings (information artifacts); Scrapbooks
- Clippings Scrapbooks, June 1921 - Sep 1989
  - Jun 1921 - Nov 1921 (Box Oversize Flat Box 1)
  - Aug 1925 - Sep 1926 (Box 1)
  - Aug 1926 - Sep 1927 (Box 1)
  - Oct 1928 - May 1935 (Box 1)
  - May 1936 - May 1937 (Box 1)
  - Aug 1938 - Apr 1939 (Box 1)
  - Aug 1939 - Sep 1940 (Box 1)
  - Aug 1940 - Sep 1941 (Box 1)
  - Aug 1941 - Sep 1942 (Box 1)
  - Jan 1942 - Dec 1944 (Box 1)
  - Oct 1944 - Oct 1946 (Box 1)
  - Sep 1946 - June 1947 (Box 1)
  - Jan 1947 - Feb 1948 (Box Oversized Flat Box 1)
  - Jan 1947 - Mar 1947 (Box 2)
  - Feb 1947 - Dec 1947 (Box 2)
  - Oct 1947 - Mar 1948 (Box Oversize Flat Box 1)
  - Jan 1948 - Jun 1948 (Box 2)
  - Feb 1948 - Dec 1948 (Box 2)
  - Mar 1948 - Dec 1948 (Box 2)
  - Jan 1949 - Mar 1949 (Box 3)
  - Jan 1949 - Aug 1950 (Box 3)
  - Apr 1949 - May 1949 (Box 2)
  - Jun 1949 - Aug 1949 (Box 2)
  - Sep 1949 - Aug 1950 (Box 3)
  - Sep 1949 - Dec 1951 (Box 2)
  - 1950s (Box 4)
  - July 1950 - Nov 1951 (Box 3)
  - Jan 1952 - Dec 1952 (Box 3)
  - Jan 1953 - Dec 1953 (Box 3)
  - Jan 1954 - Dec 1954 (Box 3)
  - Jan 1955 - Dec 1955 (Box 3)
  - Jan 1956 - Dec 1956 (Box 4)
  - Jan 1957 - Dec 1957 (Box 4)
  - Jan 1958 - Dec 1958 (Box 4)
  - Jan 1959 - Dec 1959 (Box 4)
  - May 1959 - Aug 1970 (Box Folio Volume)
    Label reads 1959 - 1968. Actual dates range from May 1959 - Aug 1970.
  - Jan 1960 - Dec 1961 (Box Folio Volume)
  - Jan 1962 - May 1962 (Box Folio Volume)
    Label on volume reads Jan 1962 - Apr 1962
  - Sep 1963 - Aug 1964 (Box Folio Volume)
  - Mar 1966 - Dec 1966 (Box Folio Volume)
  - Jan 1967 - Dec 1967 (Box Folio Volume)
  - Jan 1968 - Dec 1968 (Box Folio Volume)
  - Jan 1969 - Oct 1969 (Box Folio Volume)
  - Nov 1969 - Jun 1971 (Box Folio Volume)
  - Jun 1971 - Jun 1972 (Box Folio Volume)
  - Jul 1972 - Aug 1973 (Box Folio Volume)
  - Sep 1973 - Mar 1974 (Box Folio Volume)
  - Apr 1974 - Nov 1974 (Box Folio Volume)
  - Nov 1974 - Jun 1975 (Box Folio Volume)
  - May 1975 - Oct 1975 (Box Folio Volume)
  - Oct 1975 - Feb 1976 (Box Folio Volume)
  - Mar 1976 - Oct 1976 (Box Folio Volume)
  - Oct 1976 - Jun 1977 (Box Folio Box 1)
  - Jun 1977 - Mar 1978 (Box Folio Volume)
  - Apr 1978 - Nov 1978 (Box Folio Volume)
  - Nov 1978 - July 1979 (Box Folio Volume)
  - Jul 1979 - Feb 1980 (Box Folio Box 1)
  - Feb 1980 - Jul 1980 (Box Folio Box 1)
  - Aug 1980 - Feb 1981 (Box Folio Box 1)
  - Feb 1981 - Jul 1981 (Box Folio Box 1)
  - Jul 1981 - Dec 1981 (Box Folio Box 2)
  - Jan 1982 - Sep 1982 (Box Folio Box 2)
  - Oct 1982 - Mar 1983 (Box Folio Box 2)
  - Apr 1983 - Feb 1984 (Box Folio Box 2)
  - Feb 1984 - Aug 1984 (Box Folio Box 3)
  - Aug 1984 - Jun 1985 (Box Folio Box 3)
  - Jul 1985 - Dec 1985 (Box Folio Box 3)
  - Feb 1986 - Dec 1987 (Box Folio Box 3)
  - Jan 1987 - Dec 1987 (Box Folio Box 4)
  - Jan 1988 - Mar 1989 (Box Folio Box 4)
  - Mar 1989 - Jan 1990 (Box Folio Box 4)
  - Apr 1989 - Sep 1989 (Box Folio Box 4)
- Press Release Files, May 1998 - May 2004
  - May 1998 - Dec 1999 (Box 5)
  - Jan 2000 - May 2001 (Box 6)
  - Jun 2001 - May 2004 (Box 7)
- Loose Clippings
  - 1800s-1950s (Box 8)
  - 1960s-1990s (Box 9)